hosting-review.com 2019-07-29

# Hosting-Review Privacy Statement

### Privacy Statement

LAST UPDATED: May 25, 2018

We at www.hosting-review.com ("Hosting-Review") are committed to providing end-users with the utmost in privacy and security. 

We abide by all data protection regulations in the regions where we operate, including the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Hosting-Review is considered to be a Data Controller, as defined by the GDPR.

The English version of this policy (found at [www.hosting-review.com/terms.shtml](https://www.hosting-review.com/terms.shtml)) is the definitive version if there are any discrepancies between it and any translations provided.

By using the Hosting-Review website, you consent to the data practices described in this Privacy Policy.

Type of Information Collected

Data collected about you may include your name and email address. The “Submit a Review” form also requires you to provide a domain name and a few details about your history with the company you are reviewing. The “Contact Us” form has a general field that allows you to enter any information you volunteer to submit.

Through services like Google Analytics, we may also automatically collect information that can include your IP address, browser type, access times, and referring website addresses.

How Information is Collected

We collect information about you in two ways. You voluntarily provide information when you sign up for our newsletter or contact our staff using the “Contact Us” or the “Submit a Review” form.  

We collect information about you through the use of tools like Google Analytics and cookies. For more information about how we use cookies, please read our “Cookies” section.

Please keep in mind that personally identifiable information submitted to Hosting-Review’s review pages is visible to the public and may be collected and used by others.

Use of Information

Communications

If you sign up for the Hosting-Review newsletter, we will periodically deliver information, updates, announcements, and special offers we think you may find valuable. You can withdraw your consent to receive these communications at any time.

Hosting-Review may display targeted advertising to you. Please read the “Cookies” section below.

Web Analytics

Hosting-Review tracks visitor activity on our web pages. We use this data to enhance the browsing experience on our website by providing custom content and advertising. We may also use this data to make permanent improvements to the website’s functionality. Additionally, this data helps us to see the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and advertising.

Business Sale

If there is a change of control at Hosting-Review, like a merger or an acquisition, your personal information will be included in Hosting-Review’s sale of business assets and Hosting-Review’s new owners could have access to it. Hosting-Review will make reasonable efforts to notify you and inform you of any choices you may have about the information you shared with us.

Legal Disclosure

In order to comply with legal, regulatory, and law-enforcement requests (like court orders or for taxes), Hosting-Review may be required to disclose or process any personal information we collect.

Legal Basis

Hosting-Review has several legal bases under the GDPR for processing your personal information.

Consent: If you sign up for Hosting-Review’s newsletter, you are providing consent for us to send you the newsletter, announcements, and special offers. You can withdraw your consent for these communications at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link on any email you no longer wish to receive, or by emailing us at [info@hosting-review.com](mailto:info@hosting-review.com).

Legitimate Interest: Hosting-Review will process your personal information where it is in our legitimate interest to do so. This includes things like developing our website to better suit the needs of our visitors, detecting and preventing fraud, implementing and refining security and protective measures, and enhancing communications, including evaluating marketing campaigns.

Legal Obligation: Hosting-Review may be required to process any personal information we collect in order comply with legal, regulatory, and law-enforcement requests.

Data Storage

Location

Data we collect is stored in Canada. This means it is protected under the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). The EU also recognizes Canada as providing adequate data protection to EU residents (please see article 45 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679). This means that personal information of EU residents can be freely transferred to Canada.

Protection

Data we collect is stored on servers in a controlled, secure environment. We maintain safeguards to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification, and disclosure of this data. This includes using industry-standard SSL encryption when communicating your data. 

Please keep in mind that there is no way to give a 100% guarantee of the security of your information. Despite the measures we take, there is always a small chance that something beyond our control could allow a third party to view or tamper with data in transit.

Retention

Hosting-Review will retain your personal information for 180 days. Once that time has passed, your data is automatically deleted. 

Hosting-Review may retain personal information longer in order to comply with specific legal requests or obligations. When personal information is no longer required, we will ensure it is deleted.

Transfers

If you visit Hosting-Review from outside of Canada, your communications with Hosting-Review may result in the transfer of information across international borders. If this happens, your information will be handled under the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Changing Your Information

You may request access to review, update, and correct any inaccuracies in your personal information by or by emailing us at [info@hosting-review.com](mailto:info@hosting-review.com).

You also have the right to request that we delete your personal data. We will honor the request to the extent possible under our legal and contractual obligations.

Cookies

Hosting-Review uses “cookies” to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a small file stored by your browser at the request of a web page. Cookies are just for storing data, but they can be used in a wide variety of ways. Some cookies help us see how visitors use our sites. Others help deliver custom advertising to you as you browse. If you visit a Hosting-Review website with a browser that has cookies enabled, you are letting us know that you agree to us using cookies with your browser.

You can modify your browser settings to delete or block cookies. The exact steps depend on your browser; please see your browser help section for what you need to do. Plugins which help manage cookies are also available. If you do decide to limit your browser’s ability to use cookies, please remember that Hosting-Review sites may not function properly.

Links to Third-Party Sites

Hosting-Review has links to other websites, many of which have products and services available for purchase, or offer newsletters like we do. These links are offered as a convenience, and Hosting-Review has no control over how these third-party sites use personally identifiable information. They should have their own privacy policies, but these are separate and independent from Hosting-Review’s privacy policy. If you are thinking about making a purchase, subscribing to a newsletter or otherwise sharing your personal data with these sites, make sure to check how the third-party site will use it.

Privacy Policy Future Updates

Hosting-Review may change this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check back regularly to make sure you are aware of any changes and to stay informed of how we are protecting your information.

Contact Information

If you have any questions or comments about this privacy statement, please email us at [info@hosting-review.com](mailto:info@hosting-review.com).

You can also write to us at this address:

Hosting-Review  
5063 North Service Road, Ste 100  
Burlington, ON  
Canada L7L 5H6
